Hey, I know. Here. Yeah.
>> All right.
>> Go daddy. Come say go daddy.
>> Go.
>> Thank you.
>> Awesome. Happy to be here, guys. Um, you
know, it's a it's a unique opportunity
for us as a family. Um, you know, this
is our home. Uh, we feel passionate
about this city, this organization now.
um you know, just to be here with the
family. This is our first time, my n my
going into my 10th year in the NFL and
this is my first time having the family
here at a signing. So, um it's it's a
cool day for us and we're just happy to
be here.
>> Aside from it being home, obviously it's
a big deal, but um just what what was it
about about the Bucks and this
opportunity that that kind of excited
you? Yeah, I mean it's obviously that
that's um a big one, but at the same
time just professionally it's huge. I
think just following um and watching
film of Coach BS's defense from afar um
you know and talking to teammates that
have played here uh under him uh coaches
that have coached with him and just
seeing how I would fit and you know how
it' be used is honestly really exciting
um you know as a player. So uh you know
I feel like I'll fit fit like a glove
here. What can you bring to this defense
>> aside from maybe just your play? Your
intensity, your leadership. What are
some of those other things you can
bring?
>> Yeah, I feel like um you know, I've been
a captain in this league. Um you know, I
don't know exactly what I have in store
here, but same time, I just, you know,
try to do my best to be a great
teammate. Uh lead by example. Um you
know, just play the right play the game
with respect in the right way. And I
feel like that's that's how you garner
the respect of your teammates. And you
know that that rubs off on you know
other other teammates too. So um you
know that's really how I go about my
business and just being a pro and you
know it's got me this far so far.
>> And talking to some of your past
coaches, they they've really praised
your coverage skills. Where where does
that come from and why you think you
you've gotten so good in that
department?
>> Um yeah, I mean obviously my god-given
ability. Um I I think that's first, but
also it takes time. um you know whether
that's film study, you know, going
against your know knowing who you're
going against, studying your opponent,
um what techniques work, what what does
doesn't work, and um you know, I' I've
been asked to do a lot of that in the
past and um my time in Detroit and you
know, I'm looking to bring that here,
but um yeah, it's it's it's exciting.
>> Gwell just told us that how he beat you
on a goal pass.
>> Yeah, I mean I don't know about how I
think I I don't know if he just
necessarily beat me. Um, yeah, that was
stride for stride. So, I feel I feel
good about that. But, yeah, it's that
was the probably one of the craziest
plays of my career, honestly.
>> Uh, can he be a handful to cover?
>> For sure. Yeah, for sure. I think that
um, you know, in in my past, I was
tasked, you know, with probably the most
challenging coverage situations as far
as, you know, the linebacker core goes.
And, um, you know, usually, and that's
the tight end most most of the times.
And when we played the Steelers last
year, it was it was him. and I was like,
"Really, I'm covering the running back
this week." And um the yeah, former
receiver, a guy had does a ton of
different routes and they they need me
on him. So, um yeah, I have a ton of
respect for him just going against even
when he was in Philly. He's a great
player and a great addition.
>> What does Levante David mean to you? I
think you saw some footage and you were
saying about him. What does he mean to
you and you hope that he's coming back?
>> Yeah, he um obviously a great player. Um
you know, Hall of Fame in my opinion. I
think that um you know he's ton of
production in this league and just watch
him from afar and knowing like I said
teammates that have played with him and
uh his ability to do a lot of different
things is you know as a as a peer and a
player you you watch that and it's it's
just really cool to watch and um you
know it's I feel like I said I said this
before I don't think he's a lot of
people say he's underrated but I really
think he's just underappreciated. So,
um, you know, he's a great player and if
if that's what he has in store to come
back or, you know, say it's that's it,
it's, um, you know, either way, uh, it's
a it's been a great career for him and,
you know, we'll see what happens.
>> Have you talked to him this week?
>> No, I have not.
>> Alex, in terms of your role, is it going
to be a mic linebacker, deep linebacker
that you probably have the ability to
do?
>> Yeah, we'll see. Yeah, we'll see. Um,
you know, I think that the most exciting
thing just talking to coach Bulls the,
you know, just not like in years past, I
feel like it's my my role has been a
lot, you know, just from need in
coverage. And I feel like I'm excited
just talking to him about the, you know,
my ability to blitz, my ability to, you
know, play in the run game, not
necessarily be out of the box all the
time or, you know, manto man on a tight
end. It's going to be exciting just to,
you know, do something different than in
the past.
your Lions teammates in the building and
are you doing some salesmanship?
>> Yeah, I'm trying. I'm trying. Um yeah,
you know, me and him are close and um
you know, we're we're good friends. So,
we'll see what happens with that.
>> The Bucks and the line play each other
quite a bit you were there. What are
some of the biggest things you remember
from those matchups and maybe when you
were making this decision?
>> Yeah. Did any of that kind of come into
play?
>> For sure. I think that um you know when
you it feels like I mean I just from
even what is it like 2023 it feels like
we played several times and you get
familiar with you know an organization
or opponent and you know just like you
get you see their offense and you see
how Baker operates, how you know
different receivers operate, their O
line, the running backs um and you feel
like you kind of know them from afar
just from studying the film and playing
against them and uh you know they're
they're they're a handful and Um, you
know, it's it's cool to be a part of now
and um an offense that's explosive and,
you know, hopefully get back on track
this year and and do what they're
capable of doing.
>> In town in the offseason, are there guys
rushing, you know, just from training
with
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, I I train over here
locally in Tampa, and um yeah, I've
trained with Vita for several years, uh,
Winfield for se several years, and just
guys in and out um you know, of the
team, and I just heard nothing but great
things. And um I was actually on a
FaceTime with Vita I think yesterday,
the day before just um you know talking
about how how excited we are to you know
be be on the same team
>> as a linebacker. Pretty good to have
somebody taking up that much space for
you.
>> No doubt. No doubt. Yeah. That's
probably what I'm most excited for.
>> How often will you use a blitzer? Uh and
and how much pride do you take in that?
Yeah, it's it's like like I said, it's I
I was called to do a lot of coverage
things in the past and um you know, I
feel like that's definitely an area of
the game where I I can definitely dive
into and um when I did get my number
called I feel like I was very efficient
um you know, in my ability to rush the
passer and um I'm excited to do a little
bit more of that too.
>> BS does a lot of bling.
>> Oh yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I love it. I love
it. That's um you know you name of the
game is affecting the quarterback and um
that hopefully that's what happens.
>> Take us through just the timeline. I
know you're born in Pennsylvania.
>> When you got here in Florida, was this
for college or?
>> Yeah, college.
>> So yeah, went to went to University of
Florida. Uh met my wife Lindsay, but she
played soccer there. Um but yeah, so
after our four years there, we um you
know, spent our offseasons here in Tampa
since my rookie year. So um you know,
we've lived here for you know, what's
better than nine years. So, um, yeah,
it's it's home for us and she grew up
here and, um, it's cool to cool to be
around family and, uh, my parents aren't
far away, her parents aren't far away,
so it's just a really good situation for
us.
>> You're a high energy player.
>> You kind of envision yourself as a fire
starter on defense.
>> For sure. Yeah. Yeah. I feel like, you
know, unless you're if you're not having
fun and flying around and, you know,
doing your thing, it's it's, you know,
it's you lose the passion, especially on
the defensive side of the ball. That's
what you have to play with in my
opinion. That's what separates a lot of
great defenses from, you know, subpar
ones. And, uh, you need to have that
energy and and passion when you play.
Um, especially, like I said, especially
on defense because that's, you know,
it's an offensive league. it's a lot
skewed to to the offense and whether
that's penalties or rules or anything
like that. So, if you if you have the
ability to play with high energy and fly
around and make plays, that's what takes
a a good defense to a great defense.
>> Alex, your growth in Detroit was well
documented. Where do you feel like
you're at right now as a player and and
how can you get better?
>> Yeah. Uh yeah, there's always room for
improvement. Um there's always plays to
be made. there's always, you know,
things that you want to take back or
work on or and that's just overall. Um,
but yeah, I definitely developed and
flourished in Detroit just as a player.
I think I finally got in the right
situation and opportunity that allowed
me to do that and um, you know, whether
it's a leadership role, you know, where
positionally or things of that nature.
So, it's um, you know, it's it's what
seems like, you know, a development, it
just was I felt like it was always in
me. It's just a matter of getting in the
right situation and and uh you know just
the right fit.
>> What's your respect level?
>> Oh yeah, it's very high. Um, you know,
he's obviously I feel like his comp
competitive spirit's what everyone
thinks about when when you think of him,
but um, if you go through the film and
watch the throws that he's making, watch
the, you know, the details of the
ability to check at the line or play
the, you know, play the cat and mouse
game, um, it's high level and, you know,
it's it's good to be teammates with him.
>> How difficult has it been to live in two
spots of the of the country and
>> you could ask my wife Lindsay that right
now. Uh no. Yeah. Schools, uh doctors,
you know, moving, packing, saying bye to
friends, saying, you know, especially as
um the kids get older, it's it's it's
difficult and you know, that's a factor.
Um but at the same time, they're that's
kind of the overall decision that we
made as a family to pick home and um you
know, we're we're really excited about
it.
>> How did the process start then of
getting recruited to join the pick up,
you know, And even, you know, how many
other teams were you kind of talking to?
>> Yeah, there was se several other teams
um you know, on what was it was it on
the 9th this past Monday that were, you
know, on the table and um you know, it's
just one of those situations where you
make a decision, you sit down as a
family, talk to talk to your agent and
try to get the best fit for you. And um
you know there were other opportunities
on the table but at the same time uh you
weigh in all factors and um you know at
this point in my career I was able to
make a decision for for us and for me
personally as a professional rather than
you know some other other factors that
people choose.
>> You're close to you're used to competing
to championships.
They had a heck of a run. Yeah. And um
how close do you think this franchise
could be to uh getting that position?
>> Yeah. I mean obviously there's I think
last year for this the expectations for
this team were were you know didn't meet
the standard and um you know what I've
learned from being in Detroit at rebuild
being a part of the Saints for four
years my first four years in the league.
Um you know it doesn't take this massive
you know overhaul to do that. It's just
a piece here, a piece there. Uh adding a
player here or a coach there. That's
really what it takes. And um you know,
that's that's kind of what I've learned
through my years throughout the league.
It's like people want this, you know,
massive change like get rid of all the
player and it's that's really not what
it is. It's about getting the right
leadership in place. Um getting the
right players in place and putting
players in position to succeed. So
>> Alex, it was your first year with the
Lions in 2021. the team only won three
games. Yeah. Kind of building on that.
Yeah. From a culture perspective, what
sparked that turnout?
>> Um, you know, obviously we had a really
good leader and Dan. Um, but,
>> you know, at the end of the day, the
players are on the field and and make
the plays and, uh, we were able to, you
know, come collectively together as as a
team and, you know, kind of build a a
culture of standard and this is how we
operate. This is how we do things. This
is what it's going to take for us to
win. And, you know, that's different for
every team. It's not the same for every
team. and where we were at, we were able
to, you know, join together and and
develop that different mindset that we
needed to to turn it around and get
wins.
>> Obviously, there's a huge Gator fan base
here and you do your thing.
>> Oh, it's awesome. It's awesome. Yeah, we
uh we love our Gators and like I said,
both me and my wife are Gators. My dad
went to medical school there. So, um,
we're Gators through and through. And
just to be, you know, around other
Gators, that's awesome. Maybe a little
bit more, uh, seminals than we'd like.
Um, but at the same time, it's it's uh
it's awesome.
>> How's John Summer?
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. Awesome. Um, I'm excited
uh for what's what's in store going
going forward and um it's good to be
it's going to be awesome season, I
think. From what you've seen and studied
of the Bucks defense, do you feel like
there'll be a you feel like there'll be
a big learning curve for you that's a
complex defense or you think it'll be
kind of easy?
>> Yeah, I think that um well, I feel like
I'm a high IQ player. Um I pick up
things pretty easily, but at the same
time, yeah, there's going to be some
difference and I've been in a very
similar system my whole career, so
there's going to be some different
things that I have to, you know, figure
out for myself mentally. Um, but yeah,
it I feel like at the end of the goal,
defensive football is, you know, you try
to make it as simple as possible for you
as a defensive player, but whether it's
the look or, you know, disguise, that's
when it complicates things for the
offense. I think Coach BS does a really
good job of, you know, we're doing the
same coverage or the same thing, same
blitz look or whatever or the same
blitz, but it's a different look out of
a different picture for the offense. And
that's what really makes it look
complicated and um, you know, hard to
identify. Do
>> you have any favorite spots in town?
You've been here a while. Any places you
love to go to?
>> Um, you know this I don't know. I don't
know. Do we have any favorite spots? I
feel like we go we I mean we're we're
all over. I feel like um we went where
did we go, Cooper? The other day we went
to Busch Gardens.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. We went to Sesame Street. Um you
know, we're trying to go to Lowry Park
Zoo. Um we go to the beach all the time.
you know, we do we're just doing things
in the community that, you know, that
every other family of three kids loves
to do. So, uh, if you have any
suggestions, let me know.
>> Okay.
>> All good.
>> Yeah. Appreciate it. Thank you.